Andrew Johnson

SUMMARY

A driven Software Engineer with 5 years professional experience translating business requirements and user stories into code modules and software solutions. Comprehensive top-to-bottom experience with project management and the development lifecycle for web applications and back-end systems.

EXPERIENCE

Luther Systems, Los Gatos, CA — Software Engineer

June 2022 - November 2023

- Identified and filled in platform architectural and feature gaps while engaging in a highly dynamic and collaborative work environment.
- Developed and deployed robust RESTful APIs to support mobile and web applications, ensuring high performance and scalability.
- Optimized and streamlined QA pipeline, circumventing testing bottlenecks and resulting in a 50% increase in testing efficiency and faster product iteration.
- Designed and implemented critical functionalities including asset state versioning, rollback procedures, external library integration, and workflow optimization, enhancing platform robustness and growth potential.
- Led and facilitated team meetings, outlining story requirements and driving project progress through implementation roundtable sessions and feature workflow whiteboarding.

DataCare, San Jose, CA — Software Engineer

October 2018 - May 2022

- Engineered several client-facing, configurable modules and services that expedited key user workflows, resulting in 25% faster turnaround in document processing.
- Accelerated bug resolution, ensuring seamless operation of the platform, and exceeded client onboarding needs by delivering tailor-made features and configurations.
- Leveraged advanced SQL proficiency to craft dynamic queries for comprehensive data management and presentation, empowering both internal teams and clients with actionable insights.
- Presented and recorded thorough project demos to clients, showcasing platform features and securing buy-in for future enhancements.

RELEVANT SKILLS & TOOLS USED

Languages, Frameworks & Development - Javascript, Go (Golang), PHP, Python, Lisp, JAVA, C++, MySQL, MongoDB, JQuery, HTML, CSS, React, Django, Node.js, REST APIs

Tools & Environments - Docker, Kubernetes, Postman, Terraform, Azure DevOps, Unix, Git, GitHub, Visual Studio, PhpStorm

Project Management & QA - Agile, Scrum, Confluence, JIRA, Trello, Unit Testing, Code Review

EDUCATION

UC Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, CA — Computer Science (B.S.)

September 2014 - June 2018